<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Papers and Publications on The Bonetrade Project</title>
    <link>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Papers and Publications on The Bonetrade Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Public Lecture @ York University, What the Machine Saw</title>
      <link>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/york-05-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/york-05-29/</guid>
      <description>Note: Would begin with territorial acknowledgement, if I was in Canada. But the material I study is traded through the internet; the trade transgresses borders, it transgresses time. So I will acknowledge the land on which Carleton stands. Because those people: those people have had their ancestors bought and sold. Spoke with a scholar in sweden last month, lovely fellow, who just didn&amp;rsquo;t see why anyone should care about bones: they do not mean anything to him, therefore it follows that anyone feeling different is just misguided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Investigating and Policing Antiquities Trafficking and Forgery in a Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/stockholm-04-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/stockholm-04-25/</guid>
      <description>which presumes we know how archaeologists see Note: Sara Perry https://eprints.soton.ac.uk/344699/
 narrator: we don&amp;rsquo;t  Note: perry, hamilakis on vision, seeing, reification roopika risam on the kinds of humans our visualizations etc permit grounded &amp;amp; ungrounded antiquities try to talk about connaisseurship
pompeian wall styles
human remains
 What it would be nice to be able to do  teach the machines to understand style teach the machines to spot the differences between a forgery &amp;amp; something authentic send the machines out there to do the spotting at a scale and speed that we could never hope to achieve with our own fleshy fingers &amp;amp; imperfect eyes   ethical dangers  reification of a privileged point of view of what constitutes &amp;lsquo;style&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;material culture&amp;rsquo; automated authentication to raise the price of antiquities and fuel the trade replication of the sins of scientific racism   how neural networks beget computer vision Alex Mordvintsev</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Workshop on Quantitative Analysis and the Digital Turn in Historical Studies</title>
      <link>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/fields-02-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/fields-02-19/</guid>
      <description>Note:
 late 19th century &amp;amp; scientific racism human zoos &amp;amp; the human cost   Abraham Ulrikab Note:
 Abraham Ulrikab Moravian Christians in Labrador. Convinved to come to Europe to be part of a human zoo, because Abraham trusted, wanted to see Europe. Realized immediately the mistake. Kept a diary, translation of which was recently surfaced. Skulls and bones of him and his family found in museum collections in Paris &amp;amp; Berlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides: Cultural Property Crime Seminar</title>
      <link>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/cultpropcrime-06-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonetrade.github.io/papers/cultpropcrime-06-18/</guid>
      <description>Note:
 late 19th century &amp;amp; scientific racism human zoos &amp;amp; the human cost   Abraham Ulrikab Note:
 Abraham Ulrikab Moravian Christians in Labrador. Convinved to come to Europe to be part of a human zoo, because Abraham trusted, wanted to see Europe. Realized immediately the mistake. Kept a diary, translation of which was recently surfaced. Skulls and bones of him and his family found in museum collections in Paris &amp;amp; Berlin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>